# karlhillx@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/khill

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER OF 20+ YEARS WITH LEADERSHIP STRENGTHS

With 20+ years of experience developing and launching breakthrough solutions in Agile environments, I am a senior technology leader proven in client-facing situations. My full stack engineering background spans various industries.

## **Areas of Expertise:**

Team Leadership | SDLC Processes & Execution | Object-Oriented Design | Agile Development | UX / UI Development | Technology Implementation | Technical Troubleshooting | Project Management | Executive Collaboration | Project Management

### **EXPERIENCE**

## SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER, NASA, 2017 - Present, Science Systems and Applications, Inc. (SSAI), Greenbelt, MD

- Built an automated content registry application for NASA Earth Science Data Systems that crawls NASA domains to discover new online earth science content enriching internal data and increasing research efficiency by 40%.
- Overhauled the award-winning <u>earthobservatory.nasa.gov</u>, for NASA Earth Observatory, a public, high-traffic website with roughly 1.5 million monthly hits; streamlined site for improved performance, usability, user experience, and overall SEO.
- Spearheaded redevelopment of internal admin systems utilized by ten employees, improving functionality/reliability.
- Led software development team through Scrum ceremonies and mentored team members in Scrum best-practices.

#### SENIOR SOFWARE ENGINEER, 2016 - 2017, InformedDNA, St. Petersburg, FL

- Coded and architected a Laravel framework-based case management application for medical professionals, resulting in better usability of the previous application and saving roughly \$35K in UX/UI work.
- Expanded use with the new application and eliminated the need for three DB instances using custom APIs.
- Led development of features for the company's customer relationship management product, accelerated revenue by 15%.

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, 2012 - 2015, Ticomix, Inc., Washington, DC

- Implemented custom CRM applications for over 20 clients, including VDOT (Virginia Department of Transportation),
  Washington Redskins, and Kastle Systems, providing advanced functionality for new/existing features and amplifying sales.
- Reduced defect backlog from hundreds to 25 at launch, boosting product quality while maintaining a high customer satisfaction rating and reducing support costs for a top-tier client.
- Created applications to help companies identify qualified business opportunities, saving thousands vs. alternative solutions.

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, 2010 - 2012, Sabre Corporation, Bethesda, MD

- Developed and enhanced PHP applications in a fast-paced environment, meeting performance and reliability for five of the largest global airline, hotel, and travel agency clients.
- Liaised with marketing to drive email and social media advertising, using modeling to predict revenue.
- Mentored three junior developers and new hires, helping them improve skills and grow professionally (improving retention).

Additional roles as **Sr. Software Engineer** at **Verizon, Dante Inc, Visitar,** and **Advantage Industries,** plus two current volunteer positions at **Smithsonian's Renwick Gallery** and as a developer at **NYC Mentors.org**.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science coursework – University of MD Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD Associate of Arts (AA), General Studies – Howard Community College, Columbia, MD Certificate in Project Management – Rutgers University, Camden, NJ Certified Scrum Master (CSM) – Scrum Alliance (in-progress)

#### SKILLS

Laravel, PHP, Java, Apache, Nginx, LAMP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MVC, Webpack, Bootstrap, Tailwind, NPM, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Vue.js, Vite, Node, Git/GitHub/GitLab, REST APIs, JSON, Agile/Scrum, WordPress, Drupal, Elasticsearch, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS (Amazon Web Services), Atlassian Suite: (JIRA, Confluence), Composer, Bash and Shell